<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<introContent>
    <extensionContent id="whatsnew-top-left" style="css/style.css" name="Whats New Extension" path="whatsnew/@">
        <group style-id="content-group" id="deguitemodulestudio-introLink-group070">
            <text>A new generator setting allows control over whether the ModuleStudio version should be part of the top docblock for all generated files or only for the Version class (#627).</text>
            <text>For the generated templates YAML example files with example overrides are pregenerated for easy copy n paste (#460).</text>
            <text>Entities contain controller actions now, like any other controller elements. Therewith you can control for each entity which use cases apply.</text>
            <text>Replaced entity property mappedSuperClass by a dedicated language element.</text>
            <text>Application property applicationType has been removed.</text>
            <text>Moved data layer elements into main editor.</text>
            <text>Moved property for amount of example rows into generator settings.</text>
            <text>Moved remaining elements from controller layer into main editor.</text>
            <text>Two new properties allow controlling field visibility and css classes.</text>
            <text>Removed action handlers, action events and transitions from controller layer.</text>
            <text>Removed dsl properties for view layer, event listeners and transform objects.</text>
            <text>Updated to Eclipse 4.4.1 (Luna SR1).</text>
        </group>
        <group style-id="content-group" id="deguitemodulestudio-introLink-group062">
            <text>User avatars are displayed at appropriate places (#607).</text>
            <text>Entities with another workflow than NONE allow selecting user groups for moderation in the generated configuration page. Email notifications are sent between creator and moderators on state changes (#570).</text>
            <text>Added new DSL property (onAccountDeletion) to entities and user fields to allow control over how an app should react when users are deleted (#284).</text>
            <text>The following obsolete properties have been removed from the DSL: Application#modelPath, Application#targetCoreVersion, DerivedField#leading.</text>
            <text>All frontend functions have been converted from Prototype to jQuery and Bootstrap for Zikula 1.4.0 (#238).</text>
            <text>A new generator setting allows defining a model as system module (#596).</text>
            <text>Applications for Zikula 1.4.0 dispatch custom Symfony2 events, see generated FooEvents class (#568).</text>
            <text>Added basic support for cache annotations for 1.4.0 apps (#567).</text>
            <text>Structure of entity classes has been refactored for 1.4.0 to allow easier overriding from outside of the module using service parameters (#565).</text>
            <text>Display and delete actions use the ParamConverter annotation for object selection in 1.4.0 (#563).</text>
            <text>If no filters are set the current page of paginated views is remembered from session (#548).</text>
            <text>Applications for 1.4.0 support Monolog logger as well as Symfony components Filesystem and Finder (#546).</text>
            <text>Changed generated event subscribers for 1.4.0. Removed support for obsolete events, added support for Symfony kernel events (#544).</text>
            <text>Applications for Zikula 1.4.0 use Symfony's dependency injection container now (#535).</text>
            <text>The routing in 1.4.0 modules has been converted to Symfony using annotations. This replaces the url route classes and encodeurl/decodeurl methods generated before (#465, #604).</text>
            <text>Controller structure has been reorganised: now there exists one controller for each entity. This has been done for preparing migration to Symfony routing, but also makes controller methods more precise and easier to customise by overriding (#465).</text>
            <text>In 1.4.0 the Symfony validator component is used with annotations instead of self-written validation methods (#516).</text>
            <text>Added new options in the model editor allowing specifying additional validation constraints available in Symfony 2.4.x and 2.5.0 (#516, #606).</text>
            <text>In 1.4.0 status messages are not with LogUtil realised anymore, but using Symfony FlashBags (#512).</text>
            <text>Client-side geocoding now uses a callback function to make customisation easier inside edit templates (#507).</text>
            <text>A new dbName property for entity fields allows different naming for field and database column (#489).</text>
            <text>Array fields can be configured as array, simple array and json array for 1.4.0 (#488).</text>
            <text>Added new generator setting for marking generating files with special file names (*.generated.*) (#497).</text>
            <text>Added ics (iCalendar) templates for entities with start and end dates (#509).</text>
            <text>Migrated search integration to new helper class in 1.4.0 (#503).</text>
            <text>Updated to Eclipse 4.4 (Luna).</text>
        </group>
        <group style-id="content-group" id="deguitemodulestudio-introLink-group061">
            <text>Introduced a new model element containing generator settings. Therewith you can control which features should be generated and take influence on some behavioural aspects of the generator.</text>
            <text>Added new target core version "pre14" for the new Symfony-based module structure. This replaces the 1.3.6 version which behaves now exactly like 1.3.5.</text>
            <text>Brief entity display can now be freely controlled by a display pattern in the model. The leading flag has been marked as obsolete in the same step.</text>
            <text>Added a language property for controlling sorting also for the incoming source side of many-to-many relationships.</text>
            <text>Only string field types can be used as permalink parts (sluggable position) now.</text>
            <text>The default value for the amount of example rows to be generated for a certain model container has been changed to 0.</text>
            <text>One unrequired and confusing main menu entry (File > Open File...) has been hidden.</text>
            <text>Upload folders are now created on demand if they do not exist yet (required if a module is used without having installed it, like for example when using Multisites site templates).</text>
            <text>Added an option for bypassing entity validation (required for example when archiving objects automatically).</text>
            <text>The generator creates also a plugin for the Newsletter module (beside the Mailz plugin which has been there before already).</text>
            <text>Lists with related objects in quick navigation forms are sorted now by default.</text>
            <text>Added support for new event handlers in 1.4.0 to recognise a module being activated or deactivated.</text>
            <text>In 1.4.0 event handlers are not managed in the database anymore, but by means of dependency injection.</text>
            <text>Names of database tables include the vendor as prefix in 1.4.0.</text>
            <text>Also view actions are now allowed for ajax controllers.</text>
            <text>The frontend for 1.4.0 extensions has been converted to Bootstrap.</text>
            <text>Fixed wrong length calculation during table size validation.</text>
            <text>Added missing validation for ensuring one-to-one relations targeting a soft-deleteable entity have a remove cascade.</text>
            <text>Added missing validation for sortable group needing also a sortable position.</text>
            <text>Lots of generator bugfixes (for details see closed tickets in the MostGenerator project on Github).</text>
            <text>Updated to Eclipse 4.3.2 (Kepler SR2).</text>
        </group>
  	</extensionContent>
    <extensionContent id="whatsnew-top-right" style="css/style.css" name="Whats New Extension" path="whatsnew/@">
        <group style-id="content-group" id="news-web" label="MOST News">
            <contentProvider id="url=http://modulestudio.de/en/news.rss##welcome_items=20##no_news_url=http://modulestudio.de/en/news/##no_news_text=MOST news articles feed" pluginId="org.eclipse.ui.intro" class="org.eclipse.ui.intro.contentproviders.EclipseRSSViewer">
            </contentProvider>
        </group>
    </extensionContent>
    <extensionContent id="whatsnew-bottom-left" style="css/style.css" name="Whats New Extension" path="whatsnew/@">
        <group style-id="content-group" id="deguitemodulestudio-introLink-group060">
            <text>A new property stores the vendor of an application. Usually this is the name of a company or institution.</text>
            <text>Another new property allows you to define the desired target core version. The default is 1.3.6 which includes the new forward compatibility layer. Another current possible option is 1.3.5 for backwards compatibility.</text>
            <text>Entities with Geographical extension show a map in display and edit templates now.</text>
            <text>KML export functionality for entities with Geographical extension.</text>
            <text>When editing entities with Geographical extension a map for selecting coordinates is provided.</text>
            <text>Float and decimal fields now have a currency flag property.</text>
            <text>There are two properties for cascade settings now, one for each relation side.</text>
            <text>Handling of relations has been reimplemented with form plugins.</text>
            <text>Relationship handling is now done with dropdown lists by default. Using auto completion instead is still possible. Inline creation and editing of related items is only possible when using the auto completion approach.</text>
            <text>Integration for search and the your account panel.</text>
            <text>Basic workflow support. For each entity one of three predefined workflows can be selected and further customised by means of several options. More information can be found in the user manual.</text>
            <text>Support for pending content listener, moderation block and moderation panel.</text>
            <text>Mass handling of objects on admin view pages.</text>
            <text>Support for meta data for the Tag module.</text>
            <text>Datetime and date fields can now be declared as start or end.</text>
            <text>Automatic archiving if archive and end date are available.</text>
            <text>Using Zikula.UI.Panels in display and edit pages if they become huge.</text>
            <text>Actions in view and display pages are now presented with context menus (similar like in tree management pages).</text>
            <text>Added a quick navigation form for view pages allowing for filtering, searching and sorting the list.</text>
            <text>A new content type allows displaying one certain single object.</text>
            <text>Optional category filters for generic block and both content types.</text>
            <text>Possibility for entering custom templates in list block and list content type.</text>
            <text>A new categorisable option allows for defining whether multiple categories can be selected for the corresponding entity or not.</text>
            <text>For categories multiple registries/trees/properties are now considered everywhere.</text>
            <text>Basic Scribite integration, at the moment for Xinha and TinyMCE.</text>
            <text>Fixed storage of attributes, outsourced attribute field names into own method for easier customisation.</text>
            <text>Fixed installation of list vars by using array serialisation only for multiple lists.</text>
            <text>Allow value of 0 for list fields.</text>
            <text>Use text data type for text fields again.</text>
            <text>The function for orphan removal is now also available for many-to-many relationships (beside one-to-one and one-to-many).</text>
            <text>Fixed validation of upload file extensions; this check is now performed on the client-side, too.</text>
            <text>Upload fields can optionally have also a maximal size.</text>
            <text>Default implementation for user delete event listener.</text>
            <text>Display and edit actions have been implemented also for ajax controllers.</text>
            <text>Improved permission check instances so that permissions are considered also for single entries now.</text>
            <text>Entities with tree extension show relatives on display pages (parents, children, siblings, etc.)</text>
            <text>Fixed problems with creating root nodes in nested sets if length of title or description fields are too small.</text>
            <text>Fixed definition and handling of many-to-many relations.</text>
            <text>AutoComplete bugfixes for many-to-many and one-to-many relations.</text>
            <text>Further fixes for relation handling during edit.</text>
            <text>Removed obsolete generation of entity classes for m:n reference tables.</text>
            <text>Bugfix for deleting entities with optional upload fields.</text>
            <text>Introduced support for different types of application dependencies (requirement, recommendation, conflict) in the generator.</text>
            <text>Fixed wrong case keyword for status message determination in edit forms.</text>
            <text>Various bugfixes related with version fields and optimistic locking in the form handlers and validators.</text>
            <text>Added missing tooltip declaration in config templates.</text>
            <text>Fixed id field list retrieval in delete action.</text>
            <text>Fixed repeated object creation.</text>
            <text>Fixed modifier for displaying list field entries.</text>
            <text>Fixed logical error in validation method isStringNotContaining.</text>
            <text>Fixed usage of Gettext in JavaScript.</text>
            <text>Fixed obsolete condition for display hooks output in edit templates.</text>
            <text>Fixed list field handling in form handlers as well as in the output modifier.</text>
            <text>Fixed values for precision and scale of coordinate fields.</text>
            <text>Variables reserved in Zikula are now checked not only for field names, but also for entity names.</text>
            <text>Whitespaces are allowed now for list field entries.</text>
            <text>Fixed query for retrieving related objects during editing.</text>
            <text>Fixed validation of string fields with regular expressions.</text>
            <text>Removed wrong application of client-side validation to input buttons.</text>
            <text>Also for form plugins there are base classes generated now, for easier extensibility and customisability.</text>
            <text>Performance optimisations for the shorturl support.</text>
            <text>Usage of prepared statements in repository classes.</text>
            <text>Many minor bugfixes und refactorings in the generator (e.g. request object usage).</text>
            <text>Removed custom beautifier component as it caused more problems than benefits.</text>
            <text>Updated to Eclipse 4.2.2 (Juno SR2).</text>
            <text>Reimplemented generator templates in new language, better performance.</text>
            <text>Introduced textual syntax, also defines the new model file format.</text>
            <text>Reimplemented validation constraints, errors and warnings now also with German translation.</text>
            <text>Validation is no longer performed automatically every few seconds, but on each model save in the main editor, after opening existing models, when starting generation and when calling validation manually using the main menu.</text>
        </group>
        <group style-id="content-group" id="deguitemodulestudio-introLink-group054">
            <text>Added import of xml table definitions for migrating existing modules. See the Migrate page for more information.</text>
            <text>Further improvements for new model creation wizard.</text>
            <text>It is now possible to describe dropdowns or list fields in the model (simple lists, lists with multiple selection, checkbox lists).</text>
            <text>A new selection api simplifies data selection in controller layers.</text>
            <text>Fixed wrong regular expression in date and datetime validation inside MOST.</text>
            <text>Entity actions are now centrally collected for easier extendability and reusability.</text>
            <text>Added join relationship property to become able to distinguish between representations with normal dropdown lists and auto completion fields.</text>
            <text>Bugfix for correct initialisation of incoming m:n relations.</text>
            <text>Bugfixes for user fields in combination with tree root nodes and edit forms.</text>
            <text>It is now possible to use also now as default value for datetime, date and time field types.</text>
            <text>Validation hooks in form handlers have been armed now (errors cause abortion).</text>
            <text>Form handler refactoring outsourcing common code parts into generic parent class.</text>
            <text>Added generation of templates for custom controller actions.</text>
            <text>Config variables may contain documentation tooltips now, too.</text>
            <text>Using getOneOrNullResult method for single entity selections.</text>
            <text>Improved formatting of action icons in list views.</text>
            <text>Moved form handler base class location.</text>
            <text>Added standard fields to list of allowed sorting criteria.</text>
            <text>Parameter in image creation util class to be able to crop thumbnails individually, too.</text>
            <text>Bugfixes for error handling and post processing in form handlers.</text>
            <text>Make sort links in view templates consider the parameter for showing all items instead of paginated list properly.</text>
            <text>Improved language detection in bootstrap file when using translatable fields.</text>
            <text>Object actions in admin view templates contain now a preview icon if a user display action exists in the controller model.</text>
            <text>Fixed errors in Content type, generic block and mailz plugin.</text>
            <text>Added forgotten string field validation calls.</text>
            <text>Fixed JavaScript problems for inline editing of related objects linked by many-to-many relationships.</text>
            <text>Fixed missing generation of view modifier for displaying country names.</text>
            <text>Updated Imagine pathes for thumbnail generation due to vendor changes.</text>
        </group>
    </extensionContent>
    <extensionContent id="whatsnew-bottom-right" style="css/style.css" name="Whats New Extension" path="whatsnew/@">
    </extensionContent>
</introContent>
